Ottawa, Ontario, Canada zaidqureshi94@gmail.com www.zaid.work

#### About Zaid

Software Engineering student at the University of Ottawa, with a strong interest in mobile and web development. Always working on new projects with passion to explore software technologies. My experience includes, but not limited to, web development, Android development, and quality assurance.

#### **Education**

# BASc in Software Engineering with Engineering Management University of Ottawa

2012 to April 2016 (expected)

### **Technologies**

Ruby on Rails	JavaScript	React	Ionic	Angular
Node.js	jQuery	Java	Python	C++
С	PostgreSQL	MongoDB	PHP	Android

### **Experience**

**Cloud Developer** 

September 2015 to present

Clearwater Clinical

- Develop innovative mobile medical solutions
- Work with Amazon Web Services
- Build distributed, scalable, and highly available applications
- Wrting a RESTful API
- Unit testing and automated testing

# Mobile Application Developer Telepin Software

May 2014 to April 2015

- Developed android application for mobile payments
- Worked on cross-platform mobile application
- Designed 3 tier architecture server
- Worked with scripting and testing ussd menu
- Automated scripts for Testing Android and web applications
- Wrote documentation on Confluence for technical and non-technical personnels

## Android Application Developer

Self-Employed

- create user friendly, effcient applications
- developed 40 Rabbana Duas, 40000+ downloads
- developed Escape, 700+ downloads
- developed Line Maze
- developed One Ayah a Day
- playstore developer name: zaid.qureshi

January 2013 to Present

#### January 2013 to Present

## **Computer Science Tutor**

#### **Self-Employed**

- helped students understand basic and advanced programming concepts
- came up with exercises for the students
- provided efficient solutions for the problems students face

#### **Academic Director**

#### Software Engineering Student Association (uOttawa)

- helped students with problems in their courses
- helped arrange tech-talks
- provided students with exercises to help improve their programming skills

#### **IT Specialist Intern**

Wiconnect Corp.

- provided IT support remotely to clients, at client locations
- repaired or replaced different parents in laptops or desktops
- finished tasks within given time period, satisfied client needs
- assist IT specialists with their tasks

#### **Skills**

#### **Concepts**

- design and analysis of algorithms
- advanced knowledge of UI Evaluations
- able to perform software requirement analysis
- strong grip on OOP concepts and software architecture
- use of different data structures

#### **Tools**

- comfortable on GNU/Linux, Windows, and OS X.
- experience using Atlassian Jira and BitBucket Issues for issue tracking.
- favorite developer tools include Sublime Text, Android Studio, and IBM Eclipse
- use of Markdown, LaTeX, Vim, and Pandoc for near all text work

#### **Hobbies**

- chess
- basketball
- make programs to ease daily tasks
- fitness

#### References

Please email for more contact information and references.

September 2014 to Present

June 2013 to July 2013